大家好
Hey, guys.
你们觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
-什么啊  -什么
- About what? - What?
开玩笑吗你们  好吧我给你们一个提示
Are you kidding? Okay, I'll give you a hint.
眼睛  不  你的眼睛  不
Eyes. No, no. Your eyes! No.
钱德勒的眼睛
Chandler's eyes!
新眼镜
I got glasses.
你一直都戴眼镜
You always had glasses.
我才没有
No, I didn't.
你确定
Are you sure?
以前你没有戴眼镜吗
didn't you have a pair?
紫红色圆形的那副
They were really round and burgundy,
你戴上之后看起来有点
and they made you look kind of...
-女性化  -对
- Feminine. - Yes!
才没有
No.
眼镜好看  你戴了很性感
I think the glasses look great. You look sexy.
-真的吗   -对
- Really? - Yeah.
你没以为以前我戴眼镜吧
You didn't think I wore glasses, right?
当然没有
Of course.
订婚礼物你们想要什么
What do you want for an engagement gift?
没关系  我们不办订婚派对
That's okay, we're not having a party...
所以你们不必送我们
...so you don't have to get us...
果有人想送我们礼物
If someone wants to give us a present,
我们不该剥夺他们的快乐
we can't deprive them of that joy.
你应该送他们小型CD播放机
You should get them a little CD player.
我已经有一台了
I already have one.
除非有人借走了你那台  还丢在了妇产科医生那
Unless someone borrowed it and left it at the gynecologist.
她说"有人"  其实指的是乔伊
Yeah, and by "Someone" she means Joey.
我知道我要什么
I know what I want!
-是我们要什么  -亲爱的 你不会想要这个的
- What we want, honey. - No, you don't want this.
我要你外婆的饼干食谱
I want your grandmother's cookie recipe.
你是说巧克力碎片饼干的食谱吗
You mean the chocolate chip cookie recipe?
是那个我外婆临死前让我发誓
The one my grandma made me swear on her deathbed...
一定不能外传的食谱吗
...that I would never let out of our family?
快死的人都会胡言乱语
Dying people say the craziest things.
多年来我一直想得到它
I've wanted it for years.
我要做给我的孩子吃
I was gonna make cookies for my children.
真是割我心头肉啊  好吧
Break my heart. Oh, all right.
我即将成为
I'll be the mom
会做全世界最好吃巧克力饼干的妈妈
who makes the world's best chocolate chip cookies.
看来我们的孩子会是胖子
Our kids are gonna be fat, aren't they?
啊喂
Ahoy!
-船上玩得怎么样  -出海真不错啊
- How's the boat? - I'm getting into this sailing stuff.
这次你终于驾船驶出码头了
You finally took it out of the marina?
我为什么要那么做
Why would I do that?
我找了3个人才把它送进码头
It took three guys to get the thing in there.
如果你不想开它出海 你在船上都做些什么呢
If you don't sail it, what do you do on it?
光是坐在那里就很舒服了
It's a great place to just sit...
我什么都不做  就喝啤酒吃薯片
...hang around, drink a few beers, eat some chips.
恭喜你终于找到可以做这些事的地方了
It's good that you finally have a place to do that.
如果你想  我可以教你驾船
I could teach you to sail if you want.
-你会驾船  -我从小就开始驾船了
- You could? - I've been sailing my whole life.
我十五岁时  我爸送我一艘船
When I was 15, my dad bought me my own boat.
-你有一艘船   -不行吗  他想要安慰我
- Your own boat? - He was trying to cheer me up.
我的小马生病了
My pony was sick.
-你知道我在想什么吗   -什么
- You know what I was thinking? - What?
没事  就是想这么做
Nothing, I just like to go like this.
-今晚你要做什么   -你有讲座吗
- What are you doing tonight? - Do you have a lecture?
-没啊  怎么  -那我闲得很  怎么了
- No, why? - Then, free as a bird. What's up?
我爸想约你去打壁球
My dad wants to know if you want to play racquetball.
太棒了  爸一定很喜欢你
That's great! Dad must like you!
他从来不会约人去打壁球
He doesn't ask just anyone to play.
他没说是你  就是要找"钱西"
He didn't ask for you. He asked for "Chauncey."
我觉得应该是你
I assumed he meant you.
你纠正他了吗
Did you correct him?
没有  我觉得那样子比较好玩
No, I thought it would be more fun this way.
酷了  或许你们每周都该一起打球
Cool! Maybe you could do this every week.
你也可以坐在走廊上
Or you could sit on the porch...
确定没人偷垃圾桶
...and make sure no one steals the trashcans.
这也是他每周的行程之一
He does that every week too.
但你得让他赢  他最讨厌输了
Just so you know, you have to let him win. He hates to lose.
或许我该用左手打球
Maybe I'll play with my left hand.
你不就是左撇子吗
You're not a lefty?
有人认识我吗
Does anybody know me?
怎么了
What's wrong?
我刚到以前的公寓拿饼干食谱
I went to my old apartment to get the cookie recipe...
一场愚蠢的大火把它烧了
...and that stupid fire burned it up!
不  你为什么没有影印一份放在防火的盒子里
No! Why didn't you make a copy and keep it in a fireproof box...
并将其放在离原版至少一百码的地方呢
...and keep it at least 100 yards away from the original?
因为我很正常
Because I'm normal.
那是我外婆留给我的唯一遗产
That was the one legacy my grandmother left me.
我也知道你想要它当订婚礼物
And I know you wanted it as an engagement present.
我们得送你们订婚礼物
We have to get you an engagement present?
别担心
Don't worry about it.
可没人送我订婚礼物
No one got me an engagement present.
我没有食谱  但这个给你
I don't have the recipe, but here.
祝你们健康快乐
I wish you health and happiness.
一块放了很久的饼干
An old cookie?
不列出礼物清单 就是会发生这种事
This is what happens when you don't register for gifts.
我做了一些饼干冷冻了起来  这是最后一块
I made a batch and froze it. This is the only one left.
我们不能收
We can't accept this.
为什么
Why not?
因为它很恶心
Because it's gross.
等一下  我想我可用这块饼干猜出整个食谱
No, wait. I think I can figure out the recipe from this cookie.
我在工作时常常这么做
I do this at work all the time.
-真的吗  -我想我可以做到
- Really? - I think so!
好吧罗斯  我们欠你一份礼物
Okay, Ross, we owe you a present.
是两份  我订过两次婚
Two! I've been engaged twice.
快来看看这个小丑
Look at this clown.
他以为他拿了个大点儿的球  就能主宰整条河了
He thinks he got a bigger ball, so he can take up the whole river.
闪开  混球
Get out of the way, jackass!
话说回来谁会把自己的船命名为海岸防卫队的
Who names their boat Coast Guard, anyway?
他们就是海岸防卫队
That is the Coast Guard.
他们在这里做什么
What are they doing here?
海岸在那边
The coast is all the way over there.
乔伊  别管那些船
Joey, just ignore the boats.
-我们的课还没有上完  -好吧
- We're not finished with our lesson. - All right.
我要帮你复习一下基本要点
I'm gonna go over the basic points one more time, you ready?
别麻烦了瑞秋  我已经懂了
Come on, Rach. Not again. I got it, okay?
出海先
Let's start sailing.
我想把船开到那一船女孩旁边去
I want to go over there where that boatload of girls is.
是这样是吗  你只不过想
Is that what you wanna do? You want to give...
和那些性感姑娘打个招呼
…a shout out to the hot chicas?
没问题  来吧  水手乔伊
Okay, let's do that, Sailor Joe.
快问快答  这叫什么
Quick question, though: What's this called?
-船上的绳子  -错了
- Boat rope? - Wrong!
要怎么把主帆立起来
How do you get the mainsail up?
揉搓之
Rub it?
不  如果我说我们要转向了  你该怎么办
No. What do you do if I say we're coming about?
我说"再来一下"
I say, "Come again?"
我知道  这一题我会
I know this one. I know this one.
时间到  现在你死了
Time's up. Now you're dead.
也聋了
And deaf!
你继续开玩笑吧
You go on and make your little jokes.
如果你不知道如何航海
If you don't know what you're doing...
就会没命  你听懂了吗水手
...you will die. Am I getting through to you, sailor?
-懂了  -别只是说你懂了
- Yes. - Don't just say yes.
这不是游戏  你很可能会受伤
This isn't a game. You could get hurt out here!
你想集中注意力听我说话呢  还是想死呢
Do you want to pay attention, or do you want to die?
我想从船上打电话给钱德勒
I want to make a ship-to-shore call to Chandler.
-我吃到了肉豆蔻  -真的吗
- I definitely taste nutmeg. - You do?
你没吃到吗   那就是
You don't? Well, that's the difference...
专家跟外行人的不同
...between a professional and a layman.
没错  专家还很傲慢
That and arrogance.
嗨
Hey.
出海好玩吗
Hey. How was sailing?
我不想谈这件事
I don't want to talk about it.
你们至少可以留一整块饼干给我
You could've at least saved me a cookie.
女人太恶劣了
Women are mean!
我不敢相信
I can't believe that.
现在我外婆的遗产只剩下
Now the only thing left of my grandmother's legacy is...
这块碎屑
...this crumb.
祝你们白头偕老  婚姻美满
I wish you a long and happy marriage.
-嘿  -怎么样
- Hey. - How was it?
我玩得很开心
Well, I had a great time.
但是钱西
Chauncey, on the other hand...
我来说我来说
I will tell the story.
本来挺好  我让他赢  相处甚欢
It was going great. I let him win, we were bonding...
甚至说我可以叫他爸爸
...he even said I could call him Dad.
他要你别叫他什么
And what did he ask you not to call him?
爹地
Daddy.
事情是这样的
Look, here's the story.
我们打完球  决定去蒸气浴
We had just finished playing, and we were gonna take a steam.
我走进蒸汽室
I walk into the room...
里面雾气弥漫
...and it's really steamy.
于是我拿下眼镜  悲剧发生了
So I take off my glasses, and that's when it happened.
你们在哪
Guys?
-这边  -坐这吧孩子
- Over here. - Have a seat, son.
嘿
Hey!
-我的天啊我简直不敢相信  -我知道
- Oh, my God! I can't believe it. - I know.
你给我爸跳大腿舞
You gave my father a lap dance.
他们为什么要把那里弄的雾气弥漫
Why do they put so much steam in there?
不那么做的话  那里只能叫做"房间"
Because otherwise they'd have to call it the "Room" Room.
为什么   为什么会发生那种事
Why? Why did that have to happen?
别这样  那没有什么大不了的
Come on, it's not that big a deal.
那没有什么大不了的
Not that big a deal?
那种触摸的感觉
There was touching of things.
我知道你想和我爸搞好关系
I know you wanted to bond with my dad...
但你一定要从他那个地方开始吗
...but did you have to bond to that part?
我相信爸不会在乎的
I'm sure Dad doesn't care.
或许他会觉得很好笑
He probably thought it was funny.
会把这个故事讲好多年
He'll be telling this story for years.
我就是不希望他把这个故事讲好多年
I don't want him to tell this story for years.
他会的
Oh, but he will.
他还在讲
He still tells the story
莫妮卡试图逃出减肥营的故事
about how Monica tried to escape from fat camp.
我才没有
I wasn't escaping.
那你怎么会被卡在铁丝网上的
Then how'd you get caught in the barbed wire?
我想要救一只松鼠
I was trying to help out a squirrel.
你想吃掉它
You were trying to eat it.
如果那是你爸打来告诉你这件事
If that is your father calling to tell this story...
我们就不结婚了
...then the marriage is off!
得了啦  喂
Come on. Hello.
对不起  你打错电话了
I'm sorry, you have the wrong number.
我待会回你电话  爸  我爱你
I'll call you later, Dad. I love you.
我要去见你爸
I'm off to see your dad.
你不会穿太多了吗
Aren't you a little overdressed?
记得拿小费
You better make sure he tips you this time.
我想说服他
I figured I would try to
别再提那件事
convince him not to tell the story anymore...
我想最好的办法就是跟他面对面谈一谈
...and I figured the best way to do that was face to face.
我说的"面"指的不是他的大腿
And by "Face," I don't mean his lap.
而对的那个"面"  也不是我的屁股
And by "Face," I don't mean my ass.
我不知道  他们可没有送我们礼物
I don't know. You know, they didn't get us anything.
谢谢
Thank you!
嘿
Hey.
你好啊
Well, hello.
我们什么时候再出航  伙伴
So when are we getting back out on the water, matey?
我不知道水手是怎么说的  但我死都不要
I don't know the boat way to say this, but never!
为什么
Why not?
因为你在船上很刻薄
Because you're mean on the boat.
我只是想教会你
I was just trying to teach you.
我学会了  瑞秋很刻薄
Well, lesson learned. Rachel is mean.
对对对
Yep, yep, yep.
我还记得她驾驶她爸的船带我出海
I remember when she took me out on her dad's boat.
她完全不让我插手
She wouldn't let me help at all.
对不起  我想要你帮我
Excuse me, I wanted you to help.
但你连动都动不了
But you couldn't move...
为你穿了三件救生衣
...because you were wearing three life jackets.
你得保持对大海的敬畏之心
You have to respect the sea.
乔伊  如果你觉得我很刻薄  对不起
Joey, I'm sorry if you thought that was mean.
但我告诉你  那不是刻薄
But I tell you, that was not mean.
我爸才刻薄  以前在船上 他总会对我大吼大叫
My father is mean. He used to always yell at me on the boat.
那真的很可怕  我只是想当个称职的老师
It was horrible. I was being a really good teacher.
好老师会说"放下那罐啤酒  猪头"吗
Does a good teacher say, "Put down the beer, pinead!"
好学生会在上第一堂课时喝掉七罐啤酒
Does a good student drink seven beers during his first lesson?
是六罐半
Six and a half.
你把最后一罐从我手里打翻了  记得吗
You knocked the last one out of my hand, remember?
我不希望你被船杆打中
I didn't want you to get hit by the boom.
它的确打中我了
Well, it hit me anyway.
如果我能喝完最后一罐啤酒或许就不会那么痛
It would have hurt a lot less if I had finished that last beer.
对不起  我会试着小声点不再对你大吼大叫
I'm sorry. I will try to tone it down and stop yelling.
不会再颐指气使了吗
No bossing me around?
-不会了  -会很和蔼吗
- I won't boss you around. - And be nice?
-会很和蔼  -不穿上衣
- I'll be nice. - You'll be topless?
-乔伊  -你不是想让我好好学嘛
- Joey! - You want me to learn?
这是第二十二批 或许它们会有你外婆的神髓
Here's batch 22. Maybe these are like your grandma's.
我放了一些桔子皮  没有放肉豆蔻
This has a bit of orange peel, but no nutmeg.
试吃吧
Let's give it a shot.
自从九年级后我再也没做过这么多饼干
I haven't made so many cookies since 9th grade.
那时候为什么做  饼干义卖吗
What for, a bake sale?
不  寻常星期五晚上而已
No, just a Friday night.
这些饼干真的很好吃
These are pretty good.
但是没有第17批好吃
Yeah, but not as good as batch 17.
那是哪一批
Which one was that?
你差点吐了之后我们吃的那批
The ones we had after you almost threw up.
对  第17批确实好吃
Oh, yeah, batch 17 was good.
我可不喜欢第16批
I did not like batch 16.
我没事
I'm okay.
第17批还有剩吗  我们可以研究那些啊
Any more from the good batch? We could work off those.
只剩一块了
I think there's one from batch 17 left.
第16批  16  大家都别挡路
Batch 16. Sixteen, people, get out of the way!
乔伊  你表现得很好
Okay, Joey. You're doing really good.
现在你要站到左舷去
I just need you to step to the portside.
还记得左舷是哪一边吗
Remember talking about the portside?
记得
Oh, yeah.
不记得了
No.
是左亲爱的  但没关系  那一题太难了
It's left, sweetie, but that's okay. That's a tough one.
干嘛不直接说左边呢
Why not just say left?
好  左边
Okay, go to the left.
我说左边
The left.
过去坐
Just sit over there!
看到没   你又在大吼大叫了
You're yelling again. See that?
不我很小声  语气充满了爱意 我没有大吼大叫
Oh, no, no. Very quiet. Said with love, no yelling.
你知道吗   既然我已经坐在这里
You know what? Since I'm here,
我要在左舷喝一罐啤酒
I'm gonna have a beer on the portside.
你看到我刚刚做了什么吗
See what I did there?
风有点大  麻烦你把船绳拉紧
We're luffing a little. Can you tighten up the Cunningham?
你说了一堆我听不懂的话
You just said a bunch of stuff I don't know.
乔伊  别这样  我刚刚才教过你
Joey, come on! We just went over this.
你教我的时候  有只鸟  嘴巴里
We did that when that bird...
叨着鱼飞过去
...flew over with the fish in his mouth.
你看到了吗   那真的很恶心
Did you see it? It was gross.
我没有看到鸟或鱼
I did not see the bird or the fish!
也没有看到形状像泰森的泡沫塑料
I did not see the piece of Styrofoam shaped like Mike Tyson!
我没有看到 因为我忙着教你驾驶船只
I did not, because I was trying to teach you how to sail a boat.
很明显那是不可能的任务
Which obviously is an impossible thing to do.
你在大吼大叫  而且你没有脱掉上衣
You're yelling, and I don't see you taking your top off.
我放弃了
I quit!
-你什么意思  你不能放弃  -为什么
- What do you mean? You can't quit. - Why not?
你还没学成  格林家的人不能放弃
You're not finished! I won't have it. Greens do not quit.
格林家
Greens?
我是崔比安尼家的  崔比安尼家的就放弃
I'm a Tribbiani. Tribbianis quit.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我刚刚说格林家的人不会放弃  对吧
I just said, "Greens don't quit," didn't I?
我刚刚说格林家的人不会放弃
Did I say, "Greens don't quit"?
对  而且你还是在对我大吼大叫
Yes! And you're still yelling at me.
我没有  我只是在离你比较近的地方大吼大叫
No, I'm not yelling at you. I'm just yelling near you.
天啊  乔伊  我就跟我爸一样
Oh, God, Joey. I'm my father.
天啊  这真的太可怕了
Oh, my God. This is horrible.
我很努力不要跟我妈一样  却没有注意到这一点
I try so hard not to be my mother, I didn't see this coming.
我真的很抱歉 我只希望你能学会
I'm so sorry. I just wanted you to learn.
我学了
I did learn.
-真的吗   -没错  来吧
- Really? - Yeah, come on.
没事的
It's okay.
我知道主帆是什么
I know what a mainsail is.
我知道船桅过来时一定要低头
I know to duck when the boom comes across.
-我知道左舷是右边  -左边
- I know port is right. - Left.
该死
Damn it!
我外婆会很开心
It would make my grandmother happy...
我们想方设法要弄清楚她的食谱
...that we're trying to figure out her recipe.
我敢说她正抬头看着我们  对我们微笑
I bet she's looking up at us and smiling right now.
抬头
Looking up?
她对我真的很好 但现在她一定在地狱里
She was really nice to me, but she's in hell for sure.
我已经努力过了
Well, I've tried everything.
我放弃  我没办法成为
I give up. I'm not gonna be the mom...
做出全世界最好吃饼干的妈妈
...who makes the world's best cookies.
但我做最好吃的西兰花配油封鸭
I do make the best duck confit with broccoli raab.
小孩子很喜欢吃那道菜吧
Kids love that, right?
难道你家的亲戚都没有食谱吗
Isn't there any relative that has the recipe?
你姐姐呢
What about your sister?
不  我跟自己发过誓
No. I made a promise to myself that the next time...
除非我死掉  不然我不会再跟厄休拉说话
...I would talk to Ursula is over my dead body.
那一天将会是2032年10月15日
And that's not happening till October 15, 2032.
那天你会死掉吗
That's the day you're gonna die?
可那天我要去玩推圆盘游戏
I've got shuffleboard that day.
你这么想
That's what you think.
你外婆的朋友呢
What about friends of your grandma?
他们没有食谱吗
Wouldn't they have the recipe?
我在法国的亲戚可能知道
I may have relatives in France who would know.
我外婆说食谱是
My grandmother said she got it
她外婆"鸟巢"传给她的
from her grandmother, "Nestley Toulouse."
她叫什么名字
What was her name?
鸟巢
Nestley Toulouse.
雀巢
Nestle Toll House?
你们美国人就是没办法说好法文
You Americans always butcher the French language.
菲比  这是你外婆的食谱吗
Phoebe, is this the recipe?
是
Yes!
天啊
Oh.
我花了两天时间
I cannot believe that I spent...
研究那份食谱
...two days figuring out that recipe.
结果它一直在这里
It was here the whole time!
我知道  就是这样的事情
I know! You see, it is stuff like this...
害得你得在地狱里受苦
...which is why you're burning in hell!
就是跟你说一下
So you understand.
如果你可以不把那件事说出去 我会觉得舒服一点
I'd feel better if you didn't tell what happened.
我觉得很不好意思
I'm a little embarrassed about it.
我完全理解
I understand completely.
最可怕的事
Nothing's scarier
莫过于在岳父母面前丢脸了
than embarrassing yourself in front of your in-laws.
事实上
As a matter of fact,
事实上我开始跟朱迪交往时  我根本就没有工作
when I started dating Judy, I was unemployed.
她爸问我是干什么工作的
Her father asked me what I did for a living.
我说我是律师
I said I was a lawyer.
-他们发现事实后你怎么办  -他们一直都没有发现
- What'd you do when they found out? - They never did.
如果你看到我给他们提供法律意见 点头附和就好
So if you ever see me giving them legal advice, just nod along.
我们可以进去了吗
Shall we?
我猜这里得穿泳装才能进来
So, I guess we wear swimsuits in here.
乔伊  虽然我不愿意我也得承认
Well, Joey, I hate to admit it...
你的航海方式  真的有趣多了
...your way of sailing is a lot more fun.
你为什么不拉一下那条绳子
Why don't you give a pull on that rope?
我们没有要出海
We're not sailing.
-就拉一下  -好吧
- Just pull on it. - All right.
三明治
Sandwiches!
不然会是什么呢
What else?
这个好
Here you go.
-谢谢  -哇
- Thank you. - Oh, wow.
-你在做什么  -抱歉
- What are you doing? - Sorry.
别那么拿  好料都被你弄掉了
Not like that. You're letting all the good stuff fall out.
小心  你把烟熏牛肉给浪费了
Careful! You're wasting good pastrami!
天啊  轮到我和我爸一样了
Oh, my God. I'm my dad!